All right, joining us now is head coach
Mike Vrabel taking some time from the
owners meeting. Coach, thanks for
joining.
Thanks for having me. How are you guys?
Oh, we're doing good. You know, we're
back here doing our work. You know,
someone's got to do the work while
you're away.
It looks like you guys are working hard
right now.
So,
just to start off, you're at the owners
meeting. What's the owners meeting like
for a head coach?
Well, I think that there's a lot of
there's different committees that
sometimes you're a part of and sometimes
that you're not.
And then if you if you're not part of
those committees, then it's
more informative.
There's dialogue based on,
you know, football ops, the proposals,
refereeing, you know, every aspect that
really touches our game outside of the
the X's and O's with our players. And
there's a lot of informative meetings.
There's a lot of dialogue. There's a lot
of conversations and then ultimately,
you know, the the owners will vote on on
some of the rule proposals and
and bylaw proposals. Yep.
You seem like you're pretty active in
some of those committees, Mike. Which
ones you were part of?
Well, the you know, been having asked to
been on the competition committee
during my time at Tennessee.
That's recently something that I've
been invited back on. So, I think that
that's been fun and and been something
that I've always enjoyed is to try to,
you know, do what's best for the game,
do what's best for our fans and and find
ways to make the game better and and
safer for our players. Yep. Mike, just
want to ask you about the free agency
period. You guys signed a you know, a
number of players, but none you're
probably more familiar with than than
Kevin Byard. Coming off a great season
with Chicago. I know you spoke about him
last year, but just when you got to
Tennessee, when did you realize how
special of a of a player that he is?
Well, I think I realized how special of
a person, right? You talk about the
player, but you know, really just
from an early time there realized what
kind of special person he was as a as a
leader and as a teammate. The way that
he engaged the building, the entire
staff, the coaching staff and his
teammates. So,
you know, we started there and realized
how solid of a person he was and and
father and husband and then, you know,
he's a excellent player and he's
like we talked about last year, just
been consistent in his attitude, his
performance, his availability. So, you
know, those are a lot of things that are
positive and that he's going to
hopefully bring to our football team.
Mike, I wanted to ask you about Romeo
Doubs. Sticking with the free agents
that Mike started with. Just, you know,
some of the traits that he brings and
some of the things that maybe you hope
will translate, you know, into what Josh
wants to do and and for Drake May and
the rest of the offense.
Yeah, I think first of all, he loves
football. I mean, he is a football
junkie. He loves talking football.
You know, from the time that that we
were able to to sign him and have him
come into the building,
you know, he didn't really want to see
any of the the you know, the new
building. Yeah, he wanted to see some of
that, but he really wanted to meet with
the with Josh and and talk and meet with
Todd Downing and and meet with me about
football and and all the things that he
wants to do to continue to improve you
know, his skill set and his impact on
the team. But, you know, he's a player
that's been
really consistent over the first 4 years
of his career. Showed up in the red
zone.
You know, showed up on third down. He's
got a good savvy to him.
You know, runs the full route tree. He's
good, you know, I would say play
strength at the point of you know, the
catch point, the contested catches that
are always critical there. And you know,
continues to build savvy.
He's played a lot of football and and
he's you know, relatively young still.
So, now with free agency kicked off, now
we're closing in on the draft, little
more than 3 weeks away.
What's your cadence of communication
with Elliot and Ryan right now? Are you
talking multiple times during the day?
Do you have check-in meetings? How does
that work?
Well, we've all kind of been going
separate ways here a little bit with the
pro days. I mean, they they go out. You
know, obviously our
our scouting department is out at pro
days. Everybody will be back in.
Really looking forward to,
you know, next week when
when those draft meetings start and and
what that process looks like with our
coaching staff.
You know, going through the the players
that they were asked to to look at, to
evaluate, to to zoom interview or to
meet with
to see where that lies, the connection
and yep, you know, their willingness to
want to add that particular player
or his personality to our football team.
And then then we'll quickly transition
on to,
you know, me and Stretch and Elliot and
Ryan and the the entire personnel
department and
kind of work through each player
position by position. Paul wants to know
if you took some ibuprofen
>> and then still hosting some of the 30
visits. Sorry.
Paul wants to know if you took some
ibuprofen after your visit to Arizona
State.
No, I mean, I usually wake up the same
every day. Pretty sore.
So, Mike, I did want to ask you about
that.
Yeah, you know, um
you know, that that video got a lot of
play over the weekend with with Max. I
think it is I'm going to try this. Is it
E Ehenacho? I'm I think I'm getting that
at least close. Um
>> Max. Max. I'm going to go with Max.
Um
I I you did the same thing. You know, a
lot of that stuff with Will. And I just
I'm curious to know
>> I've done that, guys. I've done that
every pro day that I've gone to.
>> And that's why I wanted to ask you. What
do you think that's how these things go.
What do you think you you learn from
that? You know, just why why do you feel
like that's important to sort of, you
know, get a little bit of more of a
physical workout?
>> what
You you done talking, Paul? Can I
finish?
>> [laughter]
>> You can wipe the smirk off your face.
That's okay.
I I enjoy doing it because I think when
I do it with our players, I have an
understanding and idea of what each guy
at the position,
you know, looks like, feels like, you
know, reacts to to certain movements,
especially at the line of scrimmage. You
know,
guys some guys have head heavy hands,
some guys,
you know,
um
their contact balance, their core
strength, you know, all those things at
the at the line of scrimmage um that are
critical. You know, so those are things
that we always try to do.
I would say that some positions are are
better for that than others.
Yep. And Yeah. You know, normally when I
go out to the pro day, I try to be
engaged and active and try to learn
something from all the players that are
there
and the different positions.
Yep.
So, when you come back,
um you probably haven't had time to
spend any time yet, but you're going to
be in your new building. Are you looking
forward to that? And Yeah. It it is it's
amazing. You know, I mean, and I I want
to thank Robert and Jonathan
um obviously for their
committed success,
providing us with the resources that we
need to to continue to grow, to continue
to win and continue to enhance what we
do.
Uh with that being said though, there's
so many people that that helped us get
in there.
The the building group and
you know, Woody and Dan and Gail and
obviously Stretch and Jonathan working
closely together with them. You know,
just the operations and everything that
we were able to do to get over there in
a short amount of time.
Um this vision became real
in less than a year. And then be able to
get in there on Monday. Um
you know, it's just exciting to to see
everything that's new and that the when
the players come back, how excited
they're going to be. There's been a few
that have come in that we've been able
to see.
And they're certainly amazed at at what
it's like and you know, we have a great
environment to to train our players, to
meet with our players, to to build
strong connections with our players.
What what do you think is the
the biggest or the coolest thing about
it so that you've seen?
Um
man, the coolest
I I mean, I certainly think that the the
ability to, you know, walk out of a
meeting room and be in a mobile
classroom, to to be able to extend the
meeting, you know, out to a large screen
format to to stimulate the players um in
that capacity is something that that's
>> [snorts]
>> you know, a lot of teams have. I just
don't know if they have it, you know,
outside the meeting room. We walk out a
door and
there our players are.
Um
you know, just the overall the the size
and the ease and the comfort and the way
that it flows from the training room,
the locker room to the training room,
the weight room,
the way that they all those tie
together. Um Yeah, there's there's no
real gimmicks over there. It's it's just
a lot of functionality. Yeah.
It's a it's a great space. Yep.
You guys all set?
>> Yeah, I look forward to having you guys
over. I know we want to have you guys
over and and have everybody see, but
>> Yeah. you know, just tell everybody to
remain patient. You know, there's a lot
of punch lists and again, if it affects
the players, we want to fix it first and
if it Yeah. you know,
well, we're going to get to everything.
We have a long time before training
camp. And so, there's going to be little
things to fix and sometimes there's
going to be some larger items, but
everybody's going to stay patient and
and help us get through this. All right.
Well, coach, I'll go ahead.
>> I I had one one last thing real quick. I
know I talk a lot and I know
>> Whatever you got. Um I just saw Nick
Sirianni had mentioned
>> Uh Nick Sirianni had mentioned the
possibility of you guys getting together
this summer um
you know, for joint practices. Is that
something you are ready to talk about or
is that still
>> that we would we we we want to continue
to look at. And uh
you know, obviously the league has to do
their part and allow us to uh to to be
scheduled uh you know, at that point in
time. But, I think that uh you know,
that's a football team that's had a lot
of proven success and
uh would would love the opportunity to
to practice against them and and watch
them work. Yep. All right. Well, coach,
we really appreciate you taking the
time. We'll see you when you get back.